Guide to the W.H. Cowley Papers SC0196
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal papers and writings, Series 1
  - Correspondence, writings and speeches, 1922-1978; Series 1B
    - WHC report, "Report of the Freshman Week Evaluation Committee of Ohio state University", 76 pages., 1920 (Box 3, Folder 30-3)
    - WHC paper, "Recent Developments in College Instructional Methods," 14 pages., 1930 Mar 5 (Box 3, Folder 30-4)
    - WHC article, "Athletics in American Colleges," a discussion of the Carnegie Foundation report on the subject. Published in the Journal of Higher Education., 1930 Jan 29 (Box 3, Folder 30-5)
    - WHC editorial for the Journal of Higher Education (JHE) "On Individualized Instruction," pages 177-78., 1930 Mar (Box 3, Folder 30-6)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE on Rollins College course on "Evil," H.E. Hawkes and J.H. Robinson for making the student, rather than subject matter, the focus of the curriculum page 297., 1930 May (Box 3, Folder 30-7A)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE on MIT elevation of the president to be Board of Trustees Chairman., 1930 May (Box 3, Folder 30-7B)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE about proposed change of honors and pass degrees at Oxbridge, page 298., 1930 May (Box 3, Folder 30-7C)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE on the Carnegie report on athletics, pages 355-58. See 30-5., 1930 Jun (Box 3, Folder 30-8)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE on criticism and defense of the liberal arts college, pages 413-15., 1930 Oct (Box 3, Folder 30-9)
    - WHC book review for the JHE of C.C. Little's The Awakening College, pages 416-17., 1930 Oct (Box 3, Folder 30-10)
    - WHE editorial for the JHE on Hudelson's Study of Size of Classes at Minnesota, pages 276-78., 1930 Nov (Box 3, Folder 30-11)
    - WHC paper, "What is Personnel Work?" 27 typed pages., 1930 Feb (Box 3, Folder 30-12)
    - WHC report, "Report of the Vocational Information Committee of the American Council on Education," OSU, 44 typed pages., 1930 Dec 30 (Box 3, Folder 30-13)
    - WHC report, "The Junior Area of the Ohio State University," 31 pages., 1930 Jun 11 (Box 3, Folder 30-14)
    - Typescript of WHC speech discussing Donald Bridgeman's article, "Does Business Want Scholars?" Atlantic City Conference, 5 pages., 1930 Feb 2 (Box 3, Folder 30-15)
    - WHC's Ph.D. dissertation, "A Study of the Traits of Face-to-Face Leaders," University of Chicago., 1930 (Box 3, Folder 30-16)
    - Correspondence about Ph.D. Orals., 1930 Feb-Sep (Box 3, Folder 30-17A)
    - Abstract of Ph.D. dissertation, submitted to the University of Chicago Deptartment of Psychology, 10 typed pages. (Box 3, Folder 30-17B)
    - Materials collected for Ph.D. dissertation: biographical sketches of twenty-five leaders and non-leaders, quotations and notes from readings., undated (Box 3, Folder 30-17C)
    - WHC memo to President Rightmire, George W. on the OSU Junior Area., 1930 Sep 9 (Box 3, Folder 30-18)
    - WHC memo to President Rightmire, George W. on the employment of married women by Colleges and universities, 9 pages. (Box 3, Folder 30-19)
    - WHC's preliminary examination in general psychology, for his Ph.D. program at the University of Chicago., 1930 Jan 13 (Box 3, Folder 30-20)
    - WHC's preliminary examination in differential psychology, University of Chicago., 1930 Jan 15 (Box 3, Folder 30-21)
    - WHC's examination in experimental psychology, University of Chicago., 1930 Jan 17 (Box 3, Folder 30-22)
    - Seven page letter from WHC to Stevens, David H. (assistant to University of Chicago President Mason, Max) with a proposal about the future of the Board of Vocational Guidance and Placement of the University of Chicago., 1930 Jul 6 (Box 3, Folder 30-23)
    - Correspondence about Ohio State University Educational Conferenence assignment. See also 32-8, 33-3., 1930 Oct-1934 May (Box 3, Folder 30-24)
    - Miscellaneous folders:, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 30-25)
    - OSU Official Daily Bulletin announcing WHC's participation in the AAUP discussion., 1930 (Box 3, Folder 30-25A)
    - Dickson, Campbell correspondence., 1930 Mar-Jul (Box 3, Folder 30-25B)
    - WHC work and time records., 1930 (Box 3, Folder 30-25C)
    - WHC's contract for OSU., 1930, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 30-25D)
    - Summary of WHC's work on the Journal of Higher Education and his efforts to improve higher education journalism 4 typed pages., 1930-1938, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30-26)
    - WHC article, "The Traits of Face to Face Leaders," published in the Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology, pages 304-313. See also 31-18., 1931 Fall (Box 4, Folder 31-1)
    - WHC paper, "Assumptions Underlying Student Personnnel Administration," 10 typed pages., 1931 Mar 17 (Box 4, Folder 31-2)
    - WHC article, "The University and the Individual." Published in the JHE, pages 391-397. Also contains list of other articles that appeared in the same issue on the topics of A. Flexner's Universities: American, English, German., 1931 Oct (Box 4, Folder 31-3)
    - WHC article, "Evaluating Freshman Week at Ohio State University." School Review, pages 134-139., 1931 Feb (Box 4, Folder 31-4)
    - WHC report, "Stability of Mid-Term Grades at Finals, OSU College of Engineering," 32 typed pages., 1931 Mar 9 (Box 4, Folder 31-5)
    - WHC report, "The Report of the Temporary Personnel Council, OSU," 130 pages., 1931 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 31-6)
    - WHC article, "Technique of Making a Personnel Survey," The Personnel Journal., 1931 Jun (Box 4, Folder 31-7)
    - WHC article,"Two Questionnaire Devices." Published in Bulletin the Educational Research Bulletin (ERP), pages 373-76., 1931 Oct 14 (Box 4, Folder 31-8)
    - "Personnel Division," WHC article, ERB, pages 324-26., 1931 Sep 16 (Box 4, Folder 31-9)
    - WHC editorial review of first year, JHE., 1931 Jan (Box 4, Folder 31-10)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Chicago's New Curriculum.", 1931 Feb (Box 4, Folder 31-11)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Anent Wisconsin.", 1931 May (Box 4, Folder 31-12)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE "Stand-Pat Education.", 1931 Jun (Box 4, Folder 31-13)
    - WHC review of the JHE of the National Student federation of the United States of America., 1931 Oct (Box 4, Folder 31-14)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Fiscal Reflections.", 1931 Nov (Box 4, Folder 31-15)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "The University Library.", 1931 Nov (Box 4, Folder 31-15A)
    - WHC response to a letter to the editor written by Hullfish, Gordon for the JHE., 1931 Dec (Box 4, Folder 31-16)
    - WHC review for the JHE of The Autobiography of Steffens, Lincoln., 1931 Dec (Box 4, Folder 31-17)
    - WHC article, "Three Distinctions in the Study of Leaders," chapter in Business Leadership, edited by Metcalf, Henry C. pages 78-96. MISSING, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 31-18)
    - WHC report, "A Survey of the Personnel Activities of Ohio state University," 49 pages., 1931 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 31-19)
    - WHC article, "The Junior Area of Ohio State University." Published in the 9th yearbook of National Education Association Department of Superintendents, pages 150-158., 1931 Feb (Box 4, Folder 31-20)
    - Proceedings of the Ohio State Educational Conference, 45 pages., 1931 Apr 9-11 (Box 4, Folder 31-21)
    - WHC Review of Piloting Your Life, by Jastrow, Joseph. ERB, pages 53-54. NO COPY KEPT (Box 4, Folder 31-22)
    - "Salvaging Old Age," Lillian J. Martin and Carle De Gouchy, ERB, pages 113. NO COPY KEPT (Box 4, Folder 31-23)
    - "Problems of Student Guidance," Sheehy, Maurice S., ERB, page 114. NO COPY KEPT (Box 4, Folder 31-24)
    - Correspondence with Dartmouth President Hopkins, Ernest Martin about Miller, Herbert Adolphus., 1931 Jun-Sep (Box 4, Folder 31-25)
    - Miscellaneous Folders:, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 31-26)
    - Papers related to job offer from President Chase, H.W. at the University of Illinois., 1930 Nov-1931 Jan (Box 4, Folder 31-26A)
    - WHC's work resume., 1931 (Box 4, Folder 31-26B)
    - WHC's financial resume, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 31-26C)
    - Correspondence with and about Miller, Herbert A.. Correspondence with Dartmouth Archivist Cramer, Kenneth C. about Miller, H.A.., 1931-1933, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 31-27)
    - WHC proposal, "The College Student of Another Day," 21 pages., 1932 Dec (Box 4, Folder 32-1)
    - WHC report, "A Study of the Relative Merits of the Quarter and Semester Systems," OSU, 52 pages., 1932 May (Box 4, Folder 32-2)
    - WHC article, "Cooperation in American Research," published in The American Scholar, 9 pages., 1932 May (Box 4, Folder 32-3)
    - WHC report, "An Evaluation of the College of Education Survey Course for 1931," 9 pages., 1932 Jan 25 (Box 4, Folder 32-4)
    - WHC report, "Analysis of Speeded-Up Instruction of Gifted Chemistry Students," Junior Council, OSU, 3 pages., 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 32-5)
    - WHC's "Annual Report of the Personnel Division of the Bureau of Educational Research, 11 pages., 1932 Apr 15 (Box 4, Folder 32-6)
    - WHC report, "Summary of Instructional Devices Used in Junior Area Instruction," written for the OSU Junior Council, 65 pages., 1932 May (Box 4, Folder 32-7)
    - WHC report, "Report of the 12th Annual Ohio State University Educational Conference," 28 pages., 1932 Apr 7-9 (Box 4, Folder 32-8)
    - WHC report, "Stability of Mid-Term Grades at Finals," OSU College of Engineering, 10 pages., 1932 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 32-9)
    - WHC report, "A Study of the Relationship of High School Scholarship and Ohio State University Psychological Test Scores to Persistence at Ohio State University," 8 pages plus 24 tables., 1932 Nov 21 (Box 4, Folder 32-10)
    - WHC article, "Providing Information Concerning Business to College and University Students," published in Personnel, co-authored by Winans, W.H. and Esterbrooks, G.H. pages 103-113., 1932 Feb (Box 4, Folder 32-11)
    - WHC article, "Preparing for College." OSU publication, 38 pages., 1932 Dec (Box 4, Folder 32-12)
    - WHC proposal, "A Study of Student Traditions in American Colleges," OSU, 19 pages., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 32-13)
    - WHC article, "Personnel Division," published in ERB Report, 2 pages., 1932 Oct 12 (Box 4, Folder 32-14)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "The Doctors Disagree," 4 pages., 1932 Apr (Box 4, Folder 32-15)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Graduate School Admission," 3 pages., 1932 Apr (Box 4, Folder 32-16)
    - WHC review for the JHE of Ambrose Caliver's A Pesonnel Study of Negro College Students, 1 page., 1932 May (Box 4, Folder 32-17)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Socializing the College," 3 pages., 1932 Jun (Box 4, Folder 32-18)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "The Undergraduate Looks at His College," 2 pages., 1932 Jun (Box 4, Folder 32-19)
    - WHC reviews for the JHE of Selecting the College Student in America by Kurani, Habib Amin. (Box 4, Folder 32-20)
    - WHC reviews for JHE of Factors Affecting the Elimination of Women Students by Pope, Ruth Vespa. (Box 4, Folder 32-20)
    - WHC review for the JHE of A Study of Interest Test and Affectivity Test in Forecasting Freshman Success in College by Drake, Charles Arthur., 1932 Jun (Box 4, Folder 32-20)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Admissions and Differentiated Instruction.", 1932 Oct (Box 4, Folder 32-21)
    - WHC review for the JHE of American Universities and Colleges written by MacCracken, John Henry for the American Council on Education. (Box 4, Folder 32-22)
    - WHC report, "Report of the Junior Deans and of the Junior Council, 65 pages., 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 32-23)
    - Four WHC memos to himself. (Box 4, Folder 32-24A-D)
    - "Religious Tolerance in Higher Education.", undated (Box 4, Folder 32-24A)
    - "The Founding of Brown.", undated (Box 4, Folder 32-24B)
    - "The Founding of Yale.", undated (Box 4, Folder 32-24C)
    - "The Founding of Columbia.", undated (Box 4, Folder 32-24D)
    - WHC's first book, The Personnel Bibliographic Index, written at OSU, 433 pages, Hardcover Oversize., 1932 (Box 4, Folder 32-25)
    - Correspondence regarding the Personnel Bibliographic Index including letters giving reactions to the box, and magazine and newspaper reviews., 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 32-25A)
    - WHC article, "Who Produces Student Personnel Literature?" published in School and Society, 2 pages., 1932 May 7 (Box 5, Folder 32-26)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of Randolph C. Sailor's Happiness Self-Estimates of Young Men. (Box 5, Folder 32-27)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of Henry T. Tyler's "The Bearing of Personality Factors Other Than Intelligence on Academic Success." NO COPY KEPT, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 32-28)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of "How to Interview," by Bingham and Moore. (Box 5, Folder 32-29)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of Walter B. Pitkin's "The Psychology of Achievement.", 1932 Apr 27 (Box 5, Folder 32-30)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of Charles R. Gow's "Foundations for Human Engineering.", 1932 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 32-31)
    - Correspondence with Linn, James W. and Morrill, J.L. about Dartmouth Alumni Magazine article citing WHC., 1932 (Box 5, Folder 32-32)
    - Newsclippings related to WHC speech about leadership., 1932 May (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - President Hopkins, Ernest Martin correspondence about the term "personnel.", 1932 Jun-1942 Jan (Box 5, Folder 32-34)
    - Crawford and Clement acknowledgement to WHC in their book, "The Choice of An Occupation.", 1932 (Box 5, Folder 32-35)
    - Correspondence about WHC representing Dartmouth College at the inauguration of the new Butler university president., 1932 Jan 13-16 (Box 5, Folder 32-36A)
    - Letter to Mrs. A. W. Hawkes (formerly Louise Padelford) attaching WHC's 1927 discussion of Lindbergh's flight across the Atlantic., 1932 Mar 28 (Box 5, Folder 32-36B)
    - Critique of L.B. Richardson's History of Dartmouth in letter to McCarter, Bill in Hanover., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 32-36C)
    - Correspondence about WHC's writing., 1932 Oct (Box 5, Folder 32-36D)
    - Correspondence with Gavit, John Palmer about the personnel Bibliographic Index, Miller, Herbert A. and Gavit's book, College., 1931 Nov-1932 Nov (Box 5, Folder 32-36E)
    - WHC letter to Morrill, J.L. about the Ohio College Association proposed annual conference on college teaching., 1932 Jun 21 (Box 5, Folder 32-36F)
    - Correspondence with others about WHC's relationships with Keppel, Frederick P. and Jessup, Walter A. during the 1930's., 1932 Aug-1935 Oct (Box 5, Folder 32-37)
    - Papers relating to WHC's publication negotiations with American Association of University Professors. Folder includes 3 pages typed summary by WHC with an additional page of summary. Also contains letters from WHC to W.W. Charters, Boyd H. Bode and Walter P. Metzger., 1932, 1934, 1976, 1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 32-38)
    - WHC report, "Evaluation of the College of Education Freshman Survey Course, Fall Quarter, 1932," 11 pages., 1933 Jan 3 (Box 5, Folder 33-1)
    - WHC outline, "The Historical Backrounds of the Student Personnel Movement," 13 pages., 1933 Mar 16 (Box 5, Folder 33-2)
    - WHC report, "Report of the Thirteenth Annual Ohio State Educational Conference," 4 pages., 1933 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 33-3)
    - WHC article, "Conant and Dodds," published in JHE, pages 455-460., 1933 Dec (Box 5, Folder 33-4)
    - WHC's article, "The Professor's Numerous Functions," published in School and Society, 4 pages., 1933 Jul 15 (Box 5, Folder 33-5)
    - WHC article, "Evaluating Group Lecture Courses," published in the ERB, 3 pages., 1933 Apr 12 (Box 5, Folder 33-6)
    - WHC article, "An experiment in Freshman Counseling," published in the JHE, pages 245-248., 1933 May (Box 5, Folder 33-7)
    - WHC article, "A Study in College Persistence," published in the JHE, 2 pages., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-8)
    - WHC article, "Personnel Division," published in the ERB, 2 pages., 1933 Nov 15 (Box 5, Folder 33-9)
    - WHC for the JHE of Jessie M. Pangburn's The Evolution of the American Teachers College" 2 pages., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-10)
    - WHC book review for the JHE of Margaret Kiely's Comparisons of Teachers College and Liberal-Arts College Students, 2 pages., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-10A)
    - WHC review for the JHE of Helen Foss Weeks' Factors Influencing the Choice of Courses by Students in Certain Liberal Arts Colleges, 1 page., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-11)
    - Hopkins, L.B. book review for the JHE of WHC's personnel Bibliograhic Index., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-12)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "Chicago and the Six-Four-Four Plan," 2 pages., 1933 Apr (Box 5, Folder 33-13)
    - WHC book review for the JHE of Glenn Frank's Thunder and Dawn, 1 page., 1933 May (Box 5, Folder 33-14)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE "Ages of University Presidents," 2 pages., 1933 Oct (Box 5, Folder 33-15)
    - WHC editorial for the JHE, "The Cuban Students," 2 pages., 1933 Oct (Box 5, Folder 33-16)
    - Transcript of WHC speech, "We Guarantee Satisfaction," delivered at a meeting of the Association of College Union, OSU, 17 pages. See also 35-1., 1933 Dec (Box 5, Folder 33-17)
    - WHC paper, "The College of Education and the State of Ohio," written for Dean Arps, George F. 11 pages. (Box 5, Folder 33-18)
    - WHC report, "Report to the President on the Supervision of Instruction at Ohio State University," OSU Junior Council, 18 pages., 1933 Apr 14 (Box 5, Folder 33-19)
    - WHC report, "Report to the President on the Activities of the Junior Area," OSU, 18 pages., 1933 Mar 21 (Box 5, Folder 33-20)
    - WHC report, "Rating Scale for Instructors," OSU 15 pages., 1933 Nov 8 (Box 5, Folder 33-21)
    - WHC book review of Willard Waller's The Sociology of Teaching. Never published., 1933 Jan 31 (Box 5, Folder 33-22)
    - WHC review of H.J. Kussell's article "Some Practical Suggestions for the Teachers of Romance Languages," which appeared in the Modern Language Journal, pages 349-354. WHC's review, however, was never published., 1933 Jan (Box 5, Folder 33-23)
    - News report of WHC talk on student unrest, Columbus Journal Dispatch, 1 page. (Box 5, Folder 33-24)
    - WHC review for the JHE of Donald G. Tewksbury's The Founding of American Colleges and Universities Before the Civil War, 3 pages., 1933 Feb (Box 5, Folder 33-25)
    - WHC review for the JHE of Myron M. Stearns' What Kind of College is Best?, 2 pages., 1933 Oct (Box 5, Folder 33-25A)
    - WHC review for the ERB of Ruth Strang's The Role of the Teacher in Personnel Work, 2 pages., 1933 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 33-25B)
    - WHC book review for the ERB of C.R. Allen and H.A. Tieman's Managing Minds, 1 page., 1933 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 33-25C)
    - WHC article, "Vocational Monographs," in Measurement and Guidance of College Students. Published for the American Council on Eduaction, pages 165-81. MISSING (Box 5, Folder 33-26)
    - Correspondence with Stevens, James G. of the Dartmouth Education Department, about the study of higher education and educationists., 1933 Nov-1934 Jan (Box 5, Folder 33-27)
    - Summary of efforts made to interest the American Council on Education in WHC's higher educational periodicals ideas., 1933-1934, undated (Box 5, Folder 33-28)
    - "The Study of Student Traditions as a Field of Research," OSU, 21 pages., 1933 Dec 27 (Box 5, Folder 34-1)
    - "The History of Student Residential Housing," WHC article, School and Society, 14 pages. Reprinted in Structure and Style, selected and edited by Gerda Okerlund and Esther Vinson., 1934, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 34-2)
    - "Higher Education by Radio," a speech by WHC broadcast over WOSU Radio, 5 pages., 1934 Jan 11 (Box 5, Folder 34-3)
    - "Psychology and Publicity," given before the American College Publicity Association, 19 pages., 1934 Feb 17 (Box 5, Folder 34-4)
    - "Financial Retrenchment and Lower Grade Students," WHC article, Journal of Educational Research, pages 430-434., 1934 Feb 10 (Box 5, Folder 34-5)
    - Two biographical sketches of WHC, one written by WHC, and the other by an anonymous author, 15 pages., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 34-6)
    - Copy of WHC article, "How College Differs from High School," WHC article, ERB, 3 pages. (Box 5, Folder 34-7)
    - "Organizing Non-Academic Personnel for Economy," Journal of Higher Education, 7 pages., 1934 Jan (Box 5, Folder 34-8)
    - "Evaluating the Fraternity," WHC editorial for the JHE. See also 35-13., 1934 May (Box 5, Folder 34-9)
    - "The Open-Book Examination," WHC editorial for the JHE, 1 page. (Box 5, Folder 34-10)
    - "New Harvard Regulation," WHC editorial for the JHE, 2 pages., 1934 Oct (Box 5, Folder 34-11)
    - Papers relating to the Citizen's Conference on the Crisis in Education the 4th OSU Educational Conference. (Box 5, Folder 34-12)
    - Program from conference, 19 pages., 1934 Feb 14 (Box 5, Folder 34-12A)
    - "The Educational Emergency," 15 pages, pamphlet on the purpose of the educational conference, OSU., 1934 Apr 5-7 (Box 5, Folder 34-12B)
    - Conference program with an introduction by WHC although signed by Rightmire, G.W. for the ERB., 1934 Mar 14 (Box 5, Folder 34-12C)
    - Article on the conference, Ohio State Univeristy Monthly. NO COPY KEPT., 1934 May (Box 5, Folder 34-12D)
    - "A Proposed Study of the College Fraternity," draft of 63 pages proposal to be submitted by WHC with Waller, Willard to the Carnegie Corporation., circa 1934 (Box 5, Folder 34-13)
    - "An Evaluation of Faculty Ratings by College of Engineering Freshmen," OSU, 82 pages., 1934 Oct 30 (Box 5, Folder 34-14)
    - "A Technique for Manualizing Standard Practices," M.S. thesis of Price, Marie S. supervised by WHC, 101 pages., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 34-15)
    - The Personnel Bibliographic Index, promotional leaflet for WHC book., undated (Box 6, Folder 34-16)
    - "The College Guarantees Satisfaction," outline of WHC talk given in Granville, Ohio. See also, 33-17 and 35-1., 1934 Nov 2 (Box 6, Folder 34-17)
    - Studies in Lutheran Education by the Committe on the American Lutheran Conference, WHC book review of JHE. NO COPY KEPT., undated (Box 6, Folder 34-18)
    - WHC review for the JHE of A Platform for Life, by Wilkins, E.H.. (Box 6, Folder 34-19)
    - 14th Annual OSU educational conference: Citizen's Conference on the Crisis in Education. Folder contains newsclippings about the event., 1934 Apr 5-7 (Box 6, Folder 34-20)
    - Correspondence and newsclippings reviewing the OSU Student Service Program., 1934 Oct-Nov (Box 6, Folder 34-21)
    - Correspondence with Judge Anderson and son, Bob, about WHC candidacy for the Babson Institute Presidency., 1934 Oct-Dec (Box 6, Folder 34-22)
    - Kenyon presidency negotiations: folder contains 3 pages typed summary of folder contents, and correspondence with Weaver, R.A. and others, and with Kenyon librarian., 1934, 1936, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 34-23)
    - Papers relating to WHC's marriage to McCampbell, Jean., 1934 Sep 8 (Box 6, Folder 34-24)
    - WHC letter to Maclean, Norm and Kennan,Jack reporting WHC's National Youth Administration job, Morrow, Chuck episode, and WHC editing School and Society, 6 pages., 1934 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 34-25)
    - Correspondence about WHC's National Youth Administration duties., 1934 Mar-1937 Sep (Box 6, Folder 34-26)
    - Correspondence about Morrow, Chuck and Smith, Eleanor escapade at OSU., 1934 May-1938 Nov (Box 6, Folder 34-27)
    - Summary written by WHC of his relationship with Duerr, Alvan E. 3 pages. Also includes correspondence with and about Duerr., 1934-1936, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 34-28)
    - "The College Guarantees Satisfaction," WHC article, Educational Record, 21 pages. Also includes correspondence., 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 35-1)
    - "A Study of Student Life," WHC article written with Willard Waller and published in the JHE, pages 132-142. See also 35-35., 1935 Mar (Box 6, Folder 35-2)
    - "Student Discontent and Job Placement," WHC article, Personnel Journal, pages 146-150., 1935 Oct (Box 6, Folder 35-3)